Guide to the Rice Memorial Center records, 1962-2012 UA 351
Woodson Research Center, Rice University, Houston, Texas
Rice Memorial Center records
1962-2012
Woodson Research Center, Rice University, Houston, Texas https://library.rice.edu/woodson
Rice University
UA 351
1.5 Linear Feet (3 boxes)
These records mainly include information on the construction of the Ley Student Center, renovations of the Rice Memorial Center, and art exhibits.
Historical Note
The Rice Memorial Center (RMC) was built from 1957-1958. It officially opened on December 19, 1958 under the charge of John Kennedy, its first director. Over the years a variety of offices and businesses have existed in the building from the Rice Campus Store to Sammy's Cafeteria.
From 1985-1986, the Ley Student Center was added to the building providing much needed space for existing businesses and offices. This new addition was designed by Cesar Pelli and Associates who also worked on Herring Hall.
The RMC currently houses Rice Coffeehouse, and the offices of the Thresher, the Campanile, and the Rice Program Council just to name a few. In addition, the RMC's Grand Hall also hosts various campus-wide events throughout the school year.
Scope and Contents Note
These records mainly include information on the construction of the Ley Student Center, renovations of the Rice Memorial Center, and art exhibits, at Rice University.
Conditions Governing Access
This materials is open for research. Stored off-site at the Library Service Center. Please request this material via woodson@rice.edu or call 713-348-2586.
Accruals Note
Additional materials are expected for this collection.
Immediate Source of Acquisition
Donated by Julie Neisler in 2014.
Index Terms
Subjects
Universities and colleges
Document Types
photographs; letters (correspondence); reports
Places
Art
- Series I: General, 1962-2008, 176931
  - Alcohol, 1971-1979; 176929 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Basement Renovation, 1965-1966; 176938 (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - College Banners in Sammy's, 2004; 176940 (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - Contacts, n.d.; 176942 (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - Flood, 1976; 176943 (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - Ley Student Center Anniversary, October 1996; 176951 (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - RMC 50 Years Powerpoint (DVD), 2008; 176953 (Box 1, Folder 7)
  - RMC Director Reponsibilities, 1962; 176955 (Box 1, Folder 8)
  - Space Planning, 1970-1971; 176956 (Box 1, Folder 9)
  - Stationery, n.d.; 176958 (Box 1, Folder 10)
  - Steam Tunnel Gameroom (photograph), 1978-1979; 176967 (Box 1, Folder 11)
  - Vending, 1979-1983; 176968 (Box 1, Folder 12)
- Series II: Ley Student Center Construction and Renovations, 1984-1986, 176933
  - Budget, 1985-1986; 176977 (Box 1, Folder 13)
  - Construction Schedule, 1985; 176969 (Box 1, Folder 14)
  - Correspondence, 1984-1986; 176979 (Box 1, Folder 15)
  - Legal Forms, 1985-1986; 176971 (Box 1, Folder 16)
  - "Life Outside the Classroom" - Development Presentation, 1984; 176973 (Box 1, Folder 17)
  - Notes, 1985-1986; 176981 (Box 1, Folder 18)
  - Plans and Maps, 1985-1986; 176983 (Box 1, Folder 19)
  - Project Meeting Minutes and Agenda, 1985; 176984 (Box 1, Folder 20)
  - Project Meeting Minutes and Agenda, 1986; 176986 (Box 2, Folder 1)
  - Space Use Study, 1985; 176987 (Box 2, Folder 2)
  - Vest, Martha - Renovation Notebook, May 1985-February 1986; 176989 (Box 2, Folder 3)
- Series III: Exhibits, 1971-2012, 176935
  - Angel Island - Lydia Lum, 2000; 176993 (Box 2, Folder 4)
  - Art Exhibit, 1971-1972; 176995 (Box 2, Folder 5)
  - Blair Lounge, 2003; 176999 (Box 2, Folder 6)
  - Bowers, Brian, n.d.; 177000 (Box 2, Folder 7)
  - Campus Art Shows, 2002-2003; 177001 (Box 2, Folder 8)
  - Days for Darfur, 2006; 177002 (Box 2, Folder 9)
  - Ebano - The Mexican Cultural Institute in Houston, 1999; 177003 (Box 2, Folder 10)
  - Gongbi - Jamie Zhang, 2003; 177004 (Box 2, Folder 11)
  - Holocaust Exhibit, 2008; 177005 (Box 2, Folder 12)
  - Honduras Expo, 2007; 177006 (Box 2, Folder 13)
  - Loan Agreements, 2008-2012; 177007 (Box 2, Folder 14)
  - Mapas Politicos, Cerros y unas nubes, 2007; 177008 (Box 2, Folder 15)
  - Museum of Fine Arts, 1998-1999; 177009 (Box 2, Folder 16)
  - Museum of Fine Arts, 2000; 177010 (Box 2, Folder 17)
  - Museum of Fine Arts, 2001; 177011 (Box 2, Folder 18)
  - Museum of Fine Arts, 2002; 177012 (Box 2, Folder 19)
  - Museum of Fine Arts, 2003; 177013 (Box 3, Folder 1)
  - Museum of Fine Arts, 2004; 177014 (Box 3, Folder 2)
  - Museum of Fine Arts, 2005; 177015 (Box 3, Folder 3)
  - Museum of Fine Arts, 2006; 177016 (Box 3, Folder 4)
  - Museum of Fine Arts, 2007; 177017 (Box 3, Folder 5)
  - Museum of Fine Arts, 2008; 177018 (Box 3, Folder 6)
  - Museum of Fine Arts, 2009; 177019 (Box 3, Folder 7)
  - Newsprint Manifesto, 2007; 177020 (Box 3, Folder 8)
  - Permanent Art Collection, 2004-2005; 177021 (Box 3, Folder 9)
  - SOAR, 2002, 2007; 177022 (Box 3, Folder 10)
    - Subseries 1: Employee training, 183759
      - 1996-99, 183760 (Box 4, Folder 1)
      - 2000, 183761 (Box 4, Folder 2)
      - 2001-02, 183762 (Box 4, Folder 3)
      - 2002-03, 183763 (Box 4, Folder 4)
      - 2004, 183764 (Box 4, Folder 5)
      - 2006, 183765 (Box 4, Folder 6)
      - 2007, 183766 (Box 4, Folder 7)
      - 2008, 183767 (Box 4, Folder 8, Folder 9)
      - 2009-10, 183768 (Box 4, Folder 9)
  - Study Abroad, 2001-2002, 2006-2007; 177023 (Box 3, Folder 11)
  - Szyk, Arthur, 2004; 177024 (Box 3, Folder 12)
  - Upside Down and Backwards - Paul Hester, 2007; 177025 (Box 3, Folder 13)
  - The Veritas Forum, 2001-2002; 177026 (Box 3, Folder 13)
  - Visual Arts Contracts, 2006-2010, n.d.; 177027 (Box 3, Folder 15)
  - Women's History Month, 1999-2003; 177028 (Box 3, Folder 16)
- Series IV: Addendum, 183757
  - Subseries A: Administration/operations, 183758
    - Subseries 1: Employee training, 183769
      - 1996-99, 183770 (Box 4, Folder 1)
      - 2000, 183771 (Box 4, Folder 2)
      - 2001-02, 183772 (Box 4, Folder 3)
      - 2002-03, 183773 (Box 4, Folder 4)
      - 2004, 183774 (Box 4, Folder 5)
      - 2006, 183775 (Box 4, Folder 6)
      - 2007, 183776 (Box 4, Folder 7)
      - 2008, 183777 (Box 4, Folder 8)
      - 2009-10, 183778 (Box 4, Folder 9)
    - Subseries 2: Retreats, 183779
      - General, 1996-2006; 183780 (Box 4, Folder 10)
      - Timelines, 183783 (Box 4, Folder 11)
      - Budgets, 183784 (Box 4, Folder 12)
      - Staff training, 183785 (Box 4, Folder 13)
      - Coordinator debriefings, 183786 (Box 4, Folder 14)
      - Evaluations, 183792 (Box 4, Folder 15)
      - Leadership Retreat, 183787
        - 1990 general, 184727 (Box 4, Folder 16)
        - 1990 photos, 184728 (Box 4, Envelope 17)
        - 1991 general, 184729 (Box 4, Folder 18)
        - 1991 photos, 184730 (Box 4, Folder 19)
        - 1991 slides, 184731 (Box 4, Folder 20)
        - 1992 general, 184732 (Box 4, Folder 21)
        - 1992 photos, 184733 (Box 4, Folder 22)
        - 1992 slides, 184734 (Box 4, Folder 23)
        - 1993 handouts, 184735 (Box 4, Folder 24)
        - 1993 slides, 184736 (Box 4, Folder 25)
        - 1994 handouts, 184737 (Box 4, Folder 26)
        - 1995 handouts, 184738 (Box 4, Folder 27)
        - 1995 photos, 184739 (Box 4, Envelope 28)
        - 1996 handouts, 184740 (Box 4, Folder 29)
        - 1997 handouts, 184741 (Box 4, Folder 30)
        - 1997 photos, 184742 (Box 4, Envelope 31)
        - 1998 handouts, 184743 (Box 4, Folder 32)
        - 1998 photos, 184744 (Box 4, Envelope 33-34)
        - 1999 handouts, 184745 (Box 4, Folder 35)
        - 1999 audio tape, 184746 (Box 4, Folder 36)
        - 1999 photos, 184747 (Box 4, Folder 37-38)
        - 2000 handouts, 184748 (Box 4, Folder 39)
        - 2000; "Reflections on a Summer with Leadership Rice," essays by students in UNIV 310, 184749 (Box 4, Folder 40)
        - 2000 photos, 184750 (Box 4, Folder 41, Envelope 42-44)
        - 2000 audio tape, 184751 (Box 4, Envelope 45)
        - 2001 handouts, 184752 (Box 4, Folder 46)
        - 2001 photos, 184753 (Box 4, Folder 47, Envelope 48-49)
        - 2002 handouts, 184754 (Box 5, Folder 1)
        - 2002 photos, 184755 (Box 5, Envelope 2-3)
      - Impact Rice Retreat, 183799
        - General, 2000s; 183800 (Box 5, Folder 4)
        - 2003 handouts, 184756 (Box 5, Folder 5)
        - 2003 photos, 184757 (Box 5, Envelope 6)
        - 2004 handouts, 184758 (Box 5, Folder 7)
        - 2005 handouts, 184759 (Box 5, Folder 8)
        - 2006 handouts, 184760 (Box 5, Folder 9)
        - 2007 handouts, 184761 (Box 5, Folder 10)
        - 2008 handouts, 184762 (Box 5, Folder 11)
        - 2009 handouts, 184763 (Box 5, Folder 12)
        - photos n.d., 184764 (Box 5, Envelope 13-15)
    - Subseries 3: Events, 184032
      - Planning, 184033 (Box 5, Folder 16)
      - Policy, 184034 (Box 5, Folder 17)
      - Calendar, 184035 (Box 5, Folder 18)
      - President's Lecture Series, 184036 (Box 5, Folder 19)
      - Commencement, 184037 (Box 5, Folder 20)
      - Homecoming, 184038 (Box 5, Folder 21)
      - Families Weekend, 184039 (Box 5, Folder 22)
      - Centennial Celebration, 184040 (Box 5, Folder 23)
      - Elections, 184041 (Box 5, Folder 24)
      - Study break, 184042 (Box 5, Folder 25)
      - Ley Student Center 10th anniversary, 209595 (Box 5, Folder 26)
      - Scavenger hunts, 209596 (Box 5, Folder 27)
      - O-Week, 209597 (Box 5, Folder 28)
      - NOD, 2001; 209598 (Box 5, Folder 29)
    - Subseries 4: Marketing, 184043
      - General, 184044 (Box 5, Folder 30)
      - Website, 184045 (Box 5, Folder 31)
      - Brochure, 184046 (Box 5, Folder 32)
      - Advertising, 184047 (Box 5, Folder 33)
      - Logo contest, 184048 (Box 5, Folder 34)
      - Surveys, 184049 (Box 5, Folder 35)
      - Photos, 184050 (Box 6, Folder 1)
      - Newsletter, 184051 (Box 6, Folder 2)
      - Newcomer's guide, 184052 (Box 6, Folder 3)
      - Comment card, 184053 (Box 6, Folder 4)
      - Book of Clubs, 184054 (Box 6, Folder 5)
    - Subseries 5: Operational/Business files, 184070
      - History (newsclips), 209603 (Box 6)
        - Early, 209613 (Box 6, Folder 6)
        - 1998-2004, 209604 (Box 6, Folder 7)
        - 2005-08, 209605 (Box 6, Folder 8)
      - Hours, 184071 (Box 6, Folder 9)
      - Policy/procedure, 184072 (Box 6, Folder 10)
      - Organizational chart, 209623 (Box 6, Folder 11)
      - Development, 209624 (Box 6, Folder 12)
      - Coordinator job descriptions, 209608 (Box 6, Folder 13)
      - Goals, 209606 (Box 6, Folder 14)
      - Office timeline, 209607 (Box 6, Folder 15)
      - Maps, 184073 (Box 6, Folder 16)
      - Space planning, 209609 (Box 6, Folder 17)
      - Space configurations, 184075 (Box 6, Folder 18)
      - Space allocation, 209610 (Box 6, Folder 19-20)
      - Room count, 184076 (Box 6, Folder 21)
      - Key access, 184074 (Box 6, Folder 22)
      - Capital budget requests, 184091 (Box 6, Folder 23)
      - Capital improvements, 184092 (Box 6, Folder 24)
      - Expansion/renovations, 184077 (Box 6, Folder 25-27)
      - Furnishings/equipment Inventory, 184078 (Box 6, Folder 28)
      - Annual reports, 184079 (Box 6, Folder 29)
      - Legal, 184080 (Box 6, Folder 30)
      - Risk management, 184081 (Box 6, Folder 31)
      - Crisis management, 184082 (Box 6, Folder 32)
      - Data security, 184083 (Box 6, Folder 33)
      - Brookston Nursery, 184084 (Box 6, Folder 34)
      - Listserv, 184085 (Box 6, Folder 35)
      - Employee, 209643 (Box 6)
        - Appreciation, 209644 (Box 6, Folder 36)
        - Performance assessment, 209645 (Box 6, Folder 37)
        - Handbook, 209646 (Box 6, Folder 38)
      - Graduate students, 209647 (Box 6)
        - Interns, 209648 (Box 6, Folder 39)
        - Housing, 209649 (Box 6, Folder 40)
        - Graduate Student Association, 209650 (Box 6, Folder 41)
        - Practicum, 209651 (Box 6, Folder 42)
      - Blanket tax, 184090 (Box 7, Folder 1)
      - Programming fund, 184093 (Box 7, Folder 2)
      - Tetra points, 184089 (Box 7, Folder 3)
      - Greenopolis, 209652 (Box 7, Folder 4)
      - Art displays, 209653 (Box 7, Folder 5)
      - Bulletin board, 209654 (Box 7, Folder 6)
      - Candy machines, 209655 (Box 7, Folder 7)
      - Lockers, 209656 (Box 7, Folder 8)
      - Scholarship wall, 209657 (Box 7, Folder 9)
      - Trophy case, 209658 (Box 7, Folder 10)
      - Projects, 209673 (Box 7)
        - Ray Courtyard, 209674 (Box 7, Folder 11)
        - Benchmarking, 209675 (Box 7, Folder 12)
      - Programs, 209672 (Box 7)
        - First year experience, 209676 (Box 7, Folder 13)
        - Monitor, 209677 (Box 7, Folder 14)
        - Passport, 209678 (Box 7, Folder 15)
      - Transportation, 209679 (Box 7)
        - Parking, 209680 (Box 7, Folder 16)
        - Shuttle service, 209681 (Box 7, Folder 17)
        - Zip car, 209682 (Box 7, Folder 18)
        - Escort service, 209683 (Box 7, Folder 19)
        - Metro U Pass, 209684 (Box 7, Folder 20)
        - Metro Q card, 209685 (Box 7, Folder 21)
      - Satellite dishes, 209664 (Box 7, Folder 22)
      - ATM, 209665 (Box 7, Folder 23)
      - Catering services, 209666 (Box 7, Folder 24)
      - Alcohol policy, 209686 (Box 7, Folder 25)
      - Swank Motion Pictures, 209687 (Box 7, Folder 26)
      - Hazing, 209688 (Box 7, Folder 27)
      - Club sports, 209689 (Box 7, Folder 28)
      - Rice Memorial College, 209690 (Box 7, Folder 29)
      - Memos, 209691 (Box 7, Folder 30)
      - Committees, 209692 (Box 7)
        - Social Culture, 209693 (Box 7, Folder 31)
        - ID card, 209694 (Box 7, Folder 32)
        - Staff Advisory, 209695 (Box 7, Folder 33)
        - Professional Development, 209696 (Box 7, Folder 34)
        - Security, 209697 (Box 7, Folder 35)
      - Campus-wide, 209698 (Box 7)
        - Disability Services, 209699 (Box 7, Folder 36)
        - Student Affairs, 209700 (Box 7, Folder 37)
        - Alumni Affairs, 209701 (Box 7, Folder 38)
        - HACER, 209702 (Box 7, Folder 39)
        - Brochstein Pavilion, 209703 (Box 7, Folder 40)
        - Institutonal Research, 209704 (Box 7, Folder 41)
        - Rice Thresher, 209705 (Box 7, Folder 42)
        - Rice News, 209706 (Box 7, Folder 43)
        - Environmental Health & Safety, 209707 (Box 7, Folder 44)
        - University Relations, 209708 (Box 7, Folder 45)
        - Career Services, 209709 (Box 7, Folder 46)
        - Delivery Services, 209710 (Box 7, Folder 47)
        - Campus Police, 209711 (Box 7, Folder 48)
  - Subseries B: Occupants/designated areas, 184095
    - Tenant information, 209712 (Box 7, Folder 49)
    - Campus store, 184209 (Box 7, Folder 50)
    - Chapel, 184198 (Box 7, Folder 51)
    - Chapel reading room, 184202 (Box 7, Folder 52)
    - Computer lab, 184195 (Box 7, Folder 53)
    - Food services, 184192 (Box 7, Folder 54)
    - Honor Council, 184186 (Box 7, Folder 55)
    - International programs, 184180 (Box 7, Folder 56)
    - Joint Campus Ministries, 184183 (Box 7, Folder 57)
    - Kinko's, 184181 (Box 7, Folder 58)
    - KTRU, 184176 (Box 7, Folder 59)
    - Leadership Rice, 184175 (Box 7, Folder 60)
    - Retail operations, 184096 (Box 7, Folder 61)
    - Rice Programming Council, 184173 (Box 7, Folder 62)
    - RTV, 184174 (Box 7, Folder 63)
    - Sammy's, 184172 (Box 7, Folder 64)
    - Student Association, 209713 (Box 7, Folder 65)
    - University copy center, 209714 (Box 7, Folder 66)
    - Women's Resource Center, 184216 (Box 7, Folder 67)